# Nykaela Dodson

## Software Engineer

◆ Orange County, CA nykaeladodson.github.io nykaelad@gmail.com in nykaeladodson

#### **Profile**

I am a software engineer based in Orange County, California. Recently, I built Skopos, an API monitor for testing multistep API workflows for distributed systems in production. I have experience working with TypeScript, JavaScript, Ruby, Go, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, React, AWS, and Docker.

#### **Experience**

#### Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Skopos

2022 - present

skopos-api-monitoring.github.io ♂

Created Skopos, an open-source API monitoring tool designed for testing multi-step API workflows and running multiple tests in parallel.

- Designed, prototyped, and built key features pertaining to the definition, execution, scheduling, and notification components of Skopos for monitoring API tests using TypeScript, GraphQL (Apollo), Prisma, and the AWS CDK (EC2, ECS, ELB, EventBridge, SNS, Lambda, RDS, S3).
- Developed execution of API tests using state machines, enabling testing of multi-step API workflows (TypeScript, XState).
- Built notification functionality for efficient user responses to API failures with Slack, PagerDuty, and email integration (SNS, TypeScript).
- Implemented parallel execution of collections of API tests using multitenant EC2 instances hosting docker containers with ECS, resulting in faster completion of tests and auto-scaling of test execution (TypeScript, XState, Docker, EC2, ECS, ELB).
- Implemented the Skopos frontend GUI leading to an intuitive UI/UX (TypeScript, React).
- Collaborated with a remote team of engineers in multiple time zones during sprints to make key design decisions (Agile Workflow).
- Co-authored and presented a technical case study exploring Skopos.

#### Software Engineer, Open-Source Projects

2021 - 2022

- WireSnoop: An application for receiving and monitoring Webhooks (JavaScript, Express, React, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Digital Ocean Droplet, Nginx).
- Contact Manager: An application to manage contact emails and phone numbers with dynamic filtering (JavaScript, Handlebars, HTML, jQuery).
- Airline Routes Visualization Tool: View flight routes visually with dynamic filtering based on airline, source, and destination (React, JavaScript, Heroku).

#### Registered Nurse, Medical-Surgical

2020 - 2022

 Worked as a registered nurse providing care for 4-5 patients per shift with medical/surgical, oncology, and/or hospice needs in an acute care setting.

#### **Technical Skills**

#### Languages

TypeScript, JavaScript, Ruby, Go, SQL, CSS, HTML

#### Cloud

AWS (EC2, ECS, S3, RDS, SNS, EventBridge, Lambda), Heroku, Digital Ocean (Droplets)

### Other Technologies

React, Express, Jest, Docker, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, GraphQL (Apollo), RESTful APIs, Prisma, XState, Git/Github

#### **Education**

**Creighton University,** Bachelors of Science, Nursing GPA 3.72

2019 - 2020

**Chapman University,** Bachelors of Science, Health Sciences GPA 3.68 2015 - 2019